Daniel Peterschmidt

[w] http://danielpeterschmidt.com

[e] dpete93@gmail.com

[c] 760.473.7106

BIO

A passionate artist with a background in Chinese and computer science. Studied music for 14 years, photography for 6 years, and produced a feature-length student film. In the summer of 2014, studied abroad in Taiwan and mastered conversational fluency in Mandarin. With an interest in writing and design for several years, expanded skillset in a professional context at NPR as a Product Development intern.

Highly motivated; loves working on teams in a passionate, creative, and collaborative environments.

LANGUAGES

HTML5 CSS3 Javascript PHP MySQL

TOOLS

Adobe Creative Suite Sketch Sublime Text 3 Bootstrap 3 Google Analytics JIRA

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF PUGET SOUND

Bachelor of Arts, Chinese Language and Culture Minor: Computer Science Fall 2014

EXPERIENCE

Digital Producer Science Friday February 2016 - Present





Web Developer/Designer Freelance

November 2013 - January 2016

Washington, D.C.

Create mobile responsive web sites using Wordpress for clients, learn new languages and skills based on the job, communicate clearly and consistently with clients to ensure that goals are established and met on time, and if necessary, coordinate client's social media presences on Facebook and Twitter to ensure cohesive brand message.

Product Development Intern NPR

January 2015 - May 2015

Washington, D.C.

Designed standard card for NPR's Reddit AMAs for social media distribution, created original promotional art for several NPR podcasts, implemented visual and UX upgrades to NPR's iTunes homepage, wrote about social and digital media trends for the NPR Social Media Desk blog, and analyzed audience behavior and analytics over multiple social networks for NPR's podcasts.

Front-End Developer University of Puget Sound, Peer Allies September - December 2014

Tacoma, WA

Designed a responsive website (primarily using Model-view-controller software pattern, Ruby on Rails, and version control with Git) that provided support for victims of sexual assault and abuse by connecting them to a student ally, developed the user experience and interface of the site so that it shared a similar design language that corresponded to the official University website, collaborated with four group members in an Agile Scrum environment from Software Engineering class to create a comprehensive and functional product that satisfied the Stakeholder's needs.







